<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Steph's Tech Adventure]]></title>
  <link href="http://stephanniepb.github.io/blog/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://stephanniepb.github.io/blog/"/>
  <updated>2015-08-24T13:51:49-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://stephanniepb.github.io/blog/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[stephanniepb]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Madison+UX Weekend]]></title>
    <link href="http://stephanniepb.github.io/blog/blog/2015/08/24/madison-plus-ux-weekend/"/>
    <updated>2015-08-24T00:01:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://stephanniepb.github.io/blog/blog/2015/08/24/madison-plus-ux-weekend</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This past Friday and Saturday I began the process of shedding imposter syndrome. It began when I woke Saturday feeling some kind of way because of the day before. I spent an hour at war with myself trying to decide if I could continue this adventure. I took a shower, dressed and called a cab to take me to the Overture Center and I am so glad that I did. Friday I entered the Overture Center and discovered that the tech world needs me. Friday showed me the number of places just waiting for my prespective and I met with two teachers from the UW and Edgewood. One of the most intriguing speakers on Friday was Cory Gwin who wisely spoke about UX Design through the lens of Frank Llyod Wright. Another speaker Caroline Sober-James spoke eloquently of interpersonal communication between disigners and developers. I left Friday with small seeds of hope planted in my mind. Then; I attended the after-party at the Children&rsquo;s Museum where we began verbing nouns and the pharse &ldquo;Don&rsquo;t Sunday Me&rdquo; was born. I played an intriguing card game which brought me closer to my dream of owning a time machine and I had two very strong drinks before calling it a night. Saturday found me a little blurry-eyed but the first two speakers had me on the edge of my seat. Will Hacker spoke on material design and I listened carefully as he laid out why simple is best without ever saying the pharse. Then; Amanda Chueg really got my attention with the pharse &ldquo;obeying contrast guidelines is benefical to everyone.&rdquo; As a person that society sees as disabled I could have hugged her. I eagerly await the moment when the larger society will listen and understand the truth of that statement. Overall, UX Madison was a wonderful eye-opening experience and I look forward to being a part of the community that keeps it here in Madison.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Caught Between My Dreams and My Reality]]></title>
    <link href="http://stephanniepb.github.io/blog/blog/2015/08/23/caught-between-my-dreams-and-my-reality/"/>
    <updated>2015-08-23T23:50:13-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://stephanniepb.github.io/blog/blog/2015/08/23/caught-between-my-dreams-and-my-reality</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>My reality presses upon me threatening to snap my spine and sap my mind. Class ends and I lay my head in a place that is no longer mine. I wonder when the knock on the door will come as those hands will give me my eviction; Now I am a true outsider. Shafts of light crack the darkness in the form of a job, but I will have to leave scantuary to pursue it. Caught Between My Dreams And My Reality.</p>

<p>This week I missed two days of class which is out of character for me. I am usually the first one in class and among the last to leave. Tuesday I had a job interview which went really well and left me with a puzzle to solve; do I choose a path which will ensure I can keep my apartment or do I contine down this path of my tech adventure? If I felt about coding as I feel about writing I would choose coding. However; I do not feel that and so I am caught between what this adventure could be and what my life requires. I think that I could come to be more passionate about coding if I could take it at my pace instead of feeling like I need to know all of this in eleven weeks especially when it is brand new to me. So, here I sit in class everyday wondering if I should continue to choose my tech adventure or if I should choose a different path.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Many Ways to Solve a Puzzle]]></title>
    <link href="http://stephanniepb.github.io/blog/blog/2015/08/23/many-ways-to-solve-a-puzzle/"/>
    <updated>2015-08-23T23:29:54-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://stephanniepb.github.io/blog/blog/2015/08/23/many-ways-to-solve-a-puzzle</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This past week we dove deeper into the yellow world of JS as we began working on our second workbook. During the time I spent examining the problems within this workbook I kept hearing the old adage &ldquo;There are many ways to skin a cat&rdquo;; I try not to wonder when skinning cats was a thing and instead focus on the realization that there are many ways to solve a puzzle. I like that my answers do not match my classmates. I like the uniqueness and individuality found in the truth that there are many ways to solve a puzzle. I also like that my classmates can help me reach my answers although theirs are different than mine. I am eager to experience week four.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Entering the World of JS]]></title>
    <link href="http://stephanniepb.github.io/blog/blog/2015/08/22/entering-the-world-of-js/"/>
    <updated>2015-08-22T15:03:41-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://stephanniepb.github.io/blog/blog/2015/08/22/entering-the-world-of-js</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This week we have dived into the bright yellow world of JS. This world is bright yellow because our textbook &ldquo;Eloquent Javascript&rdquo; is that color. I am excited to gain a deeper understanding of the book that sat on my nightstand surrounded by my beloved fiction for serveral months.
I had opened it before Monday; but on Monday the language shifted from Heiroglyphics to English. I love that I had taken logic classes as a student because it made working with chapter one a review. Feeling this way about chapter one made it easier to seek out the challenge of code school. I discovered code school when my teacher sent me an invite through Gmail. I like the program and it is teaching me a lot. I am excited to use it but sometimes I wish I had more examples of how things should be done. This weekend I am going to start reading chapter two and see if I can work on learning Git some more.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tech Discoveries]]></title>
    <link href="http://stephanniepb.github.io/blog/blog/2015/06/19/tech-discoveries/"/>
    <updated>2015-06-19T15:24:17-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://stephanniepb.github.io/blog/blog/2015/06/19/tech-discoveries</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>  Welcome to my tech adventure! I am a writer so the thing that drew me to this class was the opportunity to learn how to create a website to house my writing in the form of short stories, poems, and a memoir. I have never been exposed to coding before and though I know my way around Word, Excel, Adobe etc. I was eager to see if I can build a career around the brains of the internet. I am never one to back down from a challenge and after completing the first week of this academy I feel as if I can be successful.
  Today, I was able to follow a set of directions completely on my own. It was a great confidence boost to sit down on my MacBook and create a github repository I am eager to see where this journey will take me. I want to be able to create websites that are easy for the public to navigate and that draw you into the organizations you are researching. I have an interest in grant writing and fundraising so I think a lot about how to draw the public into different causes.It is very difficult for me as a grant writer to tell a potential donor to look at our website if it is not &ldquo;people friendly&rdquo;. This is a passion and I am very excited to see what tools I can use to combat this problem and also I want a spring board into freedom.
  I am learning some new things that I can add to my tech bag and I am being reminded of some old favorites. The academy reminded me of Google Docs. I am still working on learning my way around this feature being that I am old school. Meaning I like carrying flash drives around on my key chain.  I am using Trello and Harvest. I am using Slacker and playing around with my Mac AirBook. I really like that we use Mac in class because it gives me an opportunity to familiarize myself with the system and build a new skill.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
