<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Steph's Tech Adventure]]></title>
  <link href="http://stephanniepb.github.io/blog/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://stephanniepb.github.io/blog/"/>
  <updated>2015-08-23T23:15:13-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://stephanniepb.github.io/blog/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[stephanniepb]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Entering the World of JS]]></title>
    <link href="http://stephanniepb.github.io/blog/blog/2015/08/22/entering-the-world-of-js/"/>
    <updated>2015-08-22T15:03:41-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://stephanniepb.github.io/blog/blog/2015/08/22/entering-the-world-of-js</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This week we have dived into the bright yellow world of JS. This world is bright yellow because our textbook &ldquo;Eloquent Javascript&rdquo; is that color. I am excited to gain a deeper understanding of the book that sat on my nightstand surrounded by my beloved fiction for serveral months.
I had opened it before Monday; but on Monday the language shifted from Heiroglyphics to English. I love that I had taken logic classes as a student because it made working with chapter one a review. Feeling this way about chapter one made it easier to seek out the challenge of code school. I discovered code school when my teacher sent me an invite through Gmail. I like the program and it is teaching me a lot. I am excited to use it but sometimes I wish I had more examples of how things should be done. This weekend I am going to start reading chapter two and see if I can work on learning Git some more.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tech Discoveries]]></title>
    <link href="http://stephanniepb.github.io/blog/blog/2015/06/19/tech-discoveries/"/>
    <updated>2015-06-19T15:24:17-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://stephanniepb.github.io/blog/blog/2015/06/19/tech-discoveries</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>  Welcome to my tech adventure! I am a writer so the thing that drew me to this class was the opportunity to learn how to create a website to house my writing in the form of short stories, poems, and a memoir. I have never been exposed to coding before and though I know my way around Word, Excel, Adobe etc. I was eager to see if I can build a career around the brains of the internet. I am never one to back down from a challenge and after completing the first week of this academy I feel as if I can be successful.
  Today, I was able to follow a set of directions completely on my own. It was a great confidence boost to sit down on my MacBook and create a github repository I am eager to see where this journey will take me. I want to be able to create websites that are easy for the public to navigate and that draw you into the organizations you are researching. I have an interest in grant writing and fundraising so I think a lot about how to draw the public into different causes.It is very difficult for me as a grant writer to tell a potential donor to look at our website if it is not &ldquo;people friendly&rdquo;. This is a passion and I am very excited to see what tools I can use to combat this problem and also I want a spring board into freedom.
  I am learning some new things that I can add to my tech bag and I am being reminded of some old favorites. The academy reminded me of Google Docs. I am still working on learning my way around this feature being that I am old school. Meaning I like carrying flash drives around on my key chain.  I am using Trello and Harvest. I am using Slacker and playing around with my Mac AirBook. I really like that we use Mac in class because it gives me an opportunity to familiarize myself with the system and build a new skill.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
